tissotshop.com 2018-12-26

# Privacy Policy

Tissot (a division of The Swatch Group (U.S.) Inc.) (hereafter, “Tissot”, “we”, “our” or “us”) values the trust you have placed in us. As part of our relationship, we recognize and respect your privacy. That is why Tissot is committed to protecting your privacy and using the information you share with us responsibly.

 This Privacy Statement (“Privacy Statement”) is designed to explain: (i) how Tissot collects, uses, processes, secures, shares and transfers information; (ii) what type(s) of information we collect; (iii) how you can edit and/or delete certain information and change preferences; and (iv) covers your access and/or use of our website Tissotshop.com. This Privacy Statement does not apply to the practices of companies that The Swatch Group (U.S.) Inc. does not own or control, or to people that Tissot does not employ or manage.

 This Privacy Statement may be updated periodically and without prior notice to you to reflect changes in our personal information practices or relevant laws. When we make changes, we will post them here. If we make material changes to this Privacy Statement we will place a notice on our website or we may send a notice to the e-mail address you provided to us. You may wish to check this section of our website from time to time, because by visiting our website, you agree to accept any such changes to this Privacy Statement. Except as otherwise mentioned herein, this Privacy Statement only addresses the use and disclosure of information we collect from you on our website.

This Privacy Statement is incorporated into, and part of our Terms of Use, which governs your access to and use of our website in general. This Privacy Statement shall be interpreted under the laws of the United States, regardless of the location, residence or nationality of individual users.

We updated our Privacy Statement on January 11, 2017 which is this Privacy Statement’s effective date.

## Types Of Information We Collect

 Tissot may collect personal information from you when you establish or update a Tissot account, enter a contest or sweepstake, participate in a survey or poll, shop online, check the status of an order or review order history, join our mailing list or our social networking sites, purchase and send a gift card or utilize our technical support or customer services. Categories of personal information collected include: your name, e-mail address, postal, billing and shipping address, phone number and credit card number. In addition, we may collect certain demographic information and maintain a record of your purchases from TISSOTSHOP.COM, The Swatch Group (US) Inc.’s, its affiliated companies’ and each of its/their respective ultimate corporate parent’s stores, authorized distributors, retailers and dealers.

We obtain certain information by automated means when you visit our website, such as the IP address of the device you use to connect to the Internet, domain type, browser version, service provider and the pages accessed. By collecting this information, we learn how to best tailor our website to our visitors and understand what products and services you might prefer. We and certain of our trusted third party providers collect this information through various means, such as "cookies" and "web beacons," each of which are discussed in more detail below.

We also collect information from third-party sources, including from social media and other websites that display authorized Tissot branding. For example, if you post a comment on our FaceBook page or send us a message on Twitter, we may collect that information as described in this Privacy Statement. We also may collect information about you from other brands within The Swatch Group (defined below) and commercially available sources (such as data aggregators and public databases). Please note that we may combine this information with other information that we collect about you and use it as described in the Privacy Statement.

## How We Use Information

Tissot uses the information we collect from you for the following purposes:

  * To process your order and answer your questions about the status of your order.
  * To provide you with periodic e-mails and mailings about Tissot merchandise, services and promotions.
  * To pre-fill fields.
  * Showing you and/or providing to you content that we think might be of interest to you, and displaying content according to your preferences and our terms.
  * To send you e-mails to help us learn more about your shopping preferences.
  * To help us improve our online store and your shopping experience.
  * To provide advertisements to you about our products and services on this and other websites.
  * To analyze user traffic patterns.
  * To protect the security or integrity of our websites and our business.
  * To contact or notify you if necessary.
  * To develop new services and products.
  * To provide services to you.
  * To comply with our legal obligations, policies and procedures.
  * As otherwise indicated in our Terms of Use.

Please note that if you use the share feature on our website to share any products with a friend, we will use your friend's name and email address to send the forwarding email. Your friend's information will not be saved in our customer or marketing databases. On occasion, we may combine information you provide with other demographic information available to us. In addition, when you provide personal information to us, we may share that information with other brands owned or licensed by Tissot, The Swatch Group (US) Inc., its ultimate corporate parent and each of its/their respective affiliates and subsidiaries’ (collectively, starting with the term “Tissot”, “The Swatch Group”), such as BALMAIN, BLANCPAIN, BREGUET, CERTINA, CK, FILK FLAK, GLASHUTTE ORIGINAL, HAMILTON, JAQUET DROZ, LEON HATOT, LONGINES, MIDO, OMEGA, RADO, SWATCH and UNION GLASHUTTE.

## Data Integrity

Tissot processes personally identifiably information only for the purposes for which it was collected and in accordance with this Privacy Statement. We review our data collection, storage and processing practices to ensure that we only collect, store and process the personally identifiably information needed to provide or improve our website, services and products or as otherwise permitted under this Privacy Statement. Notwithstanding the foregoing, we depend on you to update or correct your personally identifiably information whenever necessary.

## Mobile Marketing

You may be able to sign up to receive communications about our products and services through your mobile device by submitting your mobile telephone number and/or mobile email address on this website. If you use this feature, we will send you communications about our products, services and promotions to such email address and/or by text message and voice message. You may, at any time, opt out of receiving these communications by contacting us as specified in the "How to Contact Us" section below. Depending on the terms of your mobile phone contract, you may incur charges for receiving and sending email and text messages on your mobile device. Tissot is not responsible for these charges.

## Information We Share

Tissot will not sell or rent the personal information you provide to us online to any third party. Tissot may share information about our customers and subscribers with all other brands owned or licensed by The Swatch Group and with reputable third parties to provide better service to you. These third party providers are not authorized by us to use or disclose the information except as necessary to perform services on our behalf or comply with legal requirements. These services may include gathering, maintaining and managing customer information; providing customer services; taking and fulfilling orders; payment processing; conducting Tissot promotions, contests, sweepstakes and surveys; and communicating effectively with our subscribers, visitors and customers. We do not authorize these third parties to make any other use of your information. In addition, Tissot may share information that our subscribers and customers provide with specially chosen marketing partners. We also may share aggregated statistical or demographic information about you with third party companies in a manner that does not reveal your personal identity.

When Tissot conducts contests, sweepstakes, promotions, and surveys, or joins with other companies to do so, customers who choose to participate may be asked to provide personal information. Tissot and the other participating companies may use this information for such purposes as notifying winners and fulfilling promotional obligations, and may also cross reference customer databases to identify common customers. Information from these activities may also be used to explore future promotional opportunities or fulfill contractual obligations.

The Swatch Group may disclose your personal information to third parties (i) if it is required to do so by law, regulation or legal process (such as a court order), (ii) in response to a request by government or law enforcement authorities, (iii) when it believes disclosure is necessary or appropriate to prevent physical harm or financial loss or in connection with an investigation of suspected or actual illegal activity; (iv) enforce our Terms of Use or the terms of any of our statements or policies; or (v) protect the rights, property or safety of it, its associates or our visitors, users, subscribers or customers. In addition, The Swatch Group may share your information in connection with a substantial corporate transaction, such as a merger, consolidation, asset sale, or in the unlikely event of bankruptcy.

## Links to Other Websites

This website may contain links and conduits to other websites (“Linked Sites”). These Linked Sites may have their own privacy policies, which we strongly suggest you review if you visit any Linked Site. We are not responsible for the content of any Linked Site, any use of those websites, or the privacy practices of those websites.

## How We Protect Personal Information

 We believe we maintain appropriate administrative, technical and physical safeguards to protect the personal information you provide on this website against accidental, unlawful or unauthorized destruction, loss, alteration, access, disclosure or use and other unlawful forms of processing. We use Secure Sockets Layer ("SSL") technology to protect the transmission over the Internet of your payment card data. SSL technology encrypts your credit card number, order information and personal information before it is transmitted to protect it from being decoded by anyone other than or on behalf of Tissot. Our website also displays the VeriSign Secure Site Seal, which indicates that that portion of our website has been authenticated by VeriSign and that confidential transactions within that portion of the website are secured by SSL encryption.

You can check the security of your connection by looking at the URL line of your browser. When accessing a secure website, the first characters of the website address change from "http" to "https. If you are using a web browser or firewall that does not permit communications through secure websites, you will not be able to make purchases on our website. If you cannot access the secure server for any reason, you can place your order by calling 1-866-462-0050, Monday through Friday, between the hours of 9AM and 5PM EST, excluding holidays.

While we implement the above and other security measures to protect your information, please note that no administrative, technical and physical safeguards to protect the personal information you provide on this website or data transmitted over the Internet or any other public network can be guaranteed to be 100% secure.

## Your Security Obligations

You must protect against unauthorized access to your password and to your computer. Please sign off when finished using a shared computer. Your emails to us are not necessarily secure against interception so do not include sensitive information in them. We generally will not ask for passwords in an email and you should assume that if you get such a request, it might be fraudulent. YOU MUST DO WHAT YOU REASONABLY CAN TO ENSURE THE SECURITY OF YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION.

## Services And Products On Other Websites

We may offer some of our products and services or authorized Tissot branding on or through other websites. Information, including personally identifiably information, that you provide to those websites may be sent to us in order to deliver our products and services or collected and used by us as described in this Privacy Statement. We process, use, share and secure such information under this Privacy Statement. The affiliated websites through which our products and services and authorized Tissot branding are offered may have different privacy practices and we encourage you to read their privacy policies. We have no responsibility or liability for the practices, policies and security measures implemented by third parties on their websites.

## Third Party Applications

Our website may include Widgets, which are interactive mini-programs that run on our website to provide specific services from another company (e.g. allowing you to share a profile with your FaceBook or Twitter account or the content of the website to be commented upon and shared within a social media platform). Personal information, such as your email address, may be collected through the Widget. Cookies may also be set by the Widget to enable it to function properly. Information collected by this Widget is governed by the privacy policy of the company that created it. We have no responsibility or liability for the practices, policies and security measures implemented by such parties.

## Public Forums

When you contribute to a public area or feature, such as a chat room, bulletin board, list serve, wall, blog, wiki or other open forum that we may make available on or through our website or an authorized third-party website, the information that you submit may be made available to the general public. We do not restrict the distribution of personal information that you voluntarily disclose in these public forums, and so that information can be collected and used by others. For this reason, we recommend that you do not submit any sensitive information, including your full name, home address, phone number, other information that would enable other users to locate you, or financial information on these areas. We cannot prevent such information from being used in a manner that may violate this Privacy Statement or applicable law.

## Changes To Your TISSOTSHOP.COM Account Information

If at any time you want to change or review the information you have provided through TISSOTSHOP.COM, simply sign on to TISSOTSHOP.COM and click on "My Account" on the navigation bar. You will then be able to change any information stored in your account. Be sure to click "Save" when you complete your changes. You can also change or access this information by sending an e-mail to tissotcustomercare@swatchgroup.com or calling 1-866-462-0050. Please be sure to include or have ready your full name, address, phone number and e-mail address.

## Access And Correction

Subject to applicable law, we provide you with access to personal information we have retained about you and the ability to review, correct, update, block or delete the information where it is inaccurate. Subject to applicable law, we may limit or deny access to personal information and where providing such access is unreasonably burdensome or expensive under the circumstances. Please submit your request to the address specified in the "How to Contact Us" section below. Please include your name, email address and postal address in your request.

## Your Choices

We offer you certain choices about how we communicate with you and what information we collect from you. You may withdraw any consent you previously provided to us or object at any time on legitimate grounds to the processing of your personal information, and we will apply your Tissot approved preferences within a reasonable time going forward. You can choose not to receive marketing communications from us by clicking on the unsubscribe link in our marketing emails or contacting us as specified in the "How to Contact Us" section below. Please include your name, email address and postal address if you send us your request by email or postal mail.

## Cookies

Like many companies, we use "cookies" on this website. Cookies are bits of text that are placed on your computer's hard drive when you visit certain websites. Cookies may enhance your online experience by saving your preferences while you are visiting a particular site. We use cookies, for example, to preserve the contents of your virtual shopping cart between visits. We also use cookies to measure activity on the website and determine which areas and features of the website are the most popular. Most browsers will tell you how to stop accepting new cookies, how to be notified when you receive a new cookie and how to disable existing cookies. Without cookies, however, you may not be able to take full advantage of all our website features. For example, if you turn off cookies or refuse them, you will not be able to make purchases on the website. If you cannot access the secure server for any reason, you can place your order by calling 1-866-462-0050, Monday through Friday, between the hours of 9AM and 5PM EST, excluding holidays.

## Web Beacons

Certain pages on this website contain "web beacons" (also known as Internet tags, pixel tags and clear GIFs). Web beacons are used for internal purposes, such as to obtain the IP address of the computer that downloaded the page on which the beacon appears, the URL of the page on which the beacon appears, the time the page containing the beacon was viewed, and the type of browser used to view the page. We also retain service providers who use web beacons to assess the effectiveness of our email communications and learn what pages our visitors viewed.

## Interest Based Advertising

We may collect information about your online activities on our website to provide you with advertising about products and services tailored to your individual interests. We also may obtain information for this purpose from third-party websites on which our ads are served. This section of our Privacy Statement provides details and explains how to exercise your choices.

You may see certain ads on other websites because we work with advertising partners (including advertising networks) to engage in remarketing and retargeting activities. Our advertising partners allow us to target our messaging to users through demographic, interest-based and contextual means. These partners track your online activities over time and across websites by collecting information through automated means, including through the use of third-party cookies, web server logs, and web beacons. They use this information to show you advertisements that may be tailored to your individual interests. The information our advertising partners may collect includes data about your visits to websites that participate in the relevant advertising networks, such as the pages or advertisements you view and the actions you take on the websites. This data collection takes place both on our website and on third-party websites that participate in the ad networks. This process also helps us track the effectiveness of our marketing efforts. For example, we utilize certain of our ad partners’ targeted advertising services to show you our ads on other websites based on your prior visits to our website and other online activity. Below is a chart that lists our current advertising partners that provide these features together with corresponding links to describe how you may opt out of them.  Opting-out does not mean that you will stop receiving ads from us. It means that you still stop receiving ads from us that have been targeted to you based on your visits and browsing activity across websites over time.

Provided that a company participates in industry-developed programs designed to provide consumers choices about whether to receive targeted advertising, you also may opt out of ad network interest-based advertising generally through the Network Advertising Initiative website or by visiting <http://www.aboutads.info/choices/>.  To learn more, please visit the websites operated by the Network Advertising Initiative and Digital Advertising Alliance.

## Transmit and Transfer of Personal Information to Other Countries

If you are unsure whether this Privacy Statement is in conflict with the applicable local rules where you are located, you should not submit your or any other persons personally identifiably information to us. Anyone who accesses, uses or interacts with us, our third party providers or this website who submits personally identifiably information or provides any other information does thereby affirmatively consent to: (i) the international transmission, transfer, processing and/or storage of all such information, including personally identifiably information, to a country which may be deemed to have inadequate data protection and (ii) the collection (including by automated means through cookies and Web beacons), transmission, using, sharing and storage of such information, including personally identifiably information, as provided in this Privacy Statement.

## Phishing

 "Phishing" is a scam designed to steal your personal information. If you receive an email that looks like it is from us asking you for your personal information, do not respond. We will never request your password, user name, credit card information or other personal information through email.

## Visiting TISSOTSHOP.COM From Third-Party Sites

 If you are visiting TISSOTSHOP.COM through a link from another website or search engine, information about your visit to TISSOTSHOP.COM may be collected by the provider of the other website or search engine. We encourage you to review the privacy policies of these other websites or search engines. You may avoid disclosing your information to these other websites or search engines by entering TISSOTSHOP.COM directly into the address field of your Internet browser.

## Children's Privacy

This website is not directed to children under the age of thirteen and we do not knowingly collect personal information from children under the age of thirteen on the website. If we become aware that we have inadvertently received personal information from a visitor under the age of thirteen on this website, we will delete the information from our records; provided that such access is not unreasonably burdensome or expensive under the circumstances. We recommend that prospective users between the ages of 13 and 17 ask their parents or other legal guardians for permission before sending any information about themselves to anyone over the Internet.

## What are my California privacy rights?

Residents of the State of California may request a list of all third parties to which Tissot has disclosed personal information during the preceding year for the third parties' direct marketing purposes. If you are a California resident and want such a list, you must send a request to us at [tissotcustomercare@swatchgroup.com](mailto:tissotcustomercare@swatchgroup.com) or by contacting us at:

The Swatch Group (U.S.) Inc.

Division Tissot Customer Service

55 Metro Way Suite 1

Secaucus, NJ 07094

ATTN: Online Privacy Division

You must provide the statement "Your California Privacy Rights" in the subject field of your e-mail or on the envelope or post card and in the actual request. For all requests, please include your name, street address, city, state, and zip code. We will not accept requests via the telephone or by facsimile. We are not responsible for notices that are not labeled or sent properly, or that do not have complete information.

## How to Contact Us

If you have any questions or comments about this Privacy Statement please email us at tissotcustomercare@swatchgroup.com, call us at 1-866-462-0050 or contact us as indicated below:

The Swatch Group (U.S.) Inc.

Division Tissot Customer Service

55 Metro Way Suite 1

Secaucus, NJ 07094

ATTN: Online Privacy Division

If you would like us to update information we have about you or your preferences, please contact us as indicated below:

The Swatch Group (U.S.) Inc.

Division Tissot Customer Service

55 Metro Way Suite 1

Secaucus, NJ 07094

ATTN: Online Privacy Division
